Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that take of his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shall thy labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shall
not do any work. thou, nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
that thy maid servant, nor thy cattle,
nor thy stranger that is within thy
gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth the sea, and all that
in the midst, and rested the seventh
day. Wherefor the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day, and hallowed it. Honor thy
father and thy mother, that thy days may
be long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou shall not commit adultery. Thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not cover thy neighbor's house.
Thou shall not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus 20 1-17.
May the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus name we
pray.
Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program.
Also, keep in mind this is a live
stream, so feel free to send in your
questions that pertain to everlasting
life. We just ask that you keep them to
a two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce to you the family that'll be
taking part on the panel this evening.
Got brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody. Brother Jerome,
>> grace in peace.
>> Brother Dre,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Tanzel,
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question?
Uh yes, there are several health over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So
credit account asks in Deuteronomy 24:E5
something we must still abide by.
>> So it's Deuteronomy 24 and5 something
that we must still abide by. Brother
Dre, what you say?
Let's go read Deuteronomy 24 and verse
5. Tanzel, read it when you get it.
>> When a man have taken a new wife, he
shall not go out to war, neither shall
he be charged for any business, but he
shall be free at home one year, and
shall cheer up his wife which he hath
taken.
>> Well, we're we're uh we're not a
sovereign nation governing ourselves.
We are captives in different countries
that govern us. And in America, that law
does not exist where you
uh can take a year off. And
so you got to labor to make ends meet.
And if you got a business, you got to
see to that business to make sure that
the family stays afloat. So no,
that's all I got.
All right, brother Dre, thank you for
that answer. Hope that answered their
question. As we move on to our next one,
next one. Christy Watson says,
"Regarding the beginning of the Sabbath,
I was told that the Sabbath begins
Friday at sunset
and end Saturday at sunset." But in
Leviticus 23:32,
it says, "Even until Eve." So my
question is, is it dark?
>> All right. So, we're going to open this
up to the panel. But we also know that
just because the sun sets does not mean
it's dark out. Because the sun rises in
the east, sets in the west. And even
though it sets in the west, you still
have a whole lot of light out there on
the west. So that does not say
specifically that the Sabbath has kicked
in. It has to be dark. Let's um open
this up to the panel, but I would like
to also start in um
uh let's go Nehemiah. Let's go to
Nehemiah.
2 Chronicles, Ezra, and then you have
the book of Nehemiah.
And let's go to um chapter 13
and let's read
the verse 19. And let's see what it says
here because this is going to let you
know that dark was on the way, but it
wasn't quite here yet.
Nehemiah 13:9. Go ahead.
And it came to pass that when the gates
of Jerusalem began to be dark before the
Sabbath, I command
>> began to be dark before the Sabbath. So
darkness is on its way. Not quite there
yet, but it began to be dark before the
Sabbath. Go ahead.
>> I commanded that the gates should be
shut and charged that they should not be
open till after the Sabbath. and some of
my servants set I at the gates that
there should no burden be brought in on
the Sabbath day.
>> So we see that it was beginning to be
dark and it wasn't quite the Sabbath
yet. It was before the Sabbath, but when
darkness kicked in, so did the Sabbath?
Anybody else?
>> Well, you can go to Proverbs
>> 7. Uh
yeah, Proverbs 7. Go there and read it.
That sells it.
Yep. Proverbs 7 and9 that it
>> in the twilight in the evening in the
black and dark night.
>> That's it.
>> Y
>> that's it. Have to be dark.
>> Yep. When it's dark out, that's when the
Sabbath begins. When it's dark out is
once the Sabbath is over.
All right.
>> Go ahead. Say that again.
>> That's the black and dark night.
>> Yeah.
>> Let you know there's no light.
>> That's all I got to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Little Mama Hayes asks in
Matthew 18 10-14,
"The little ones are who? And is t h i r
a typo?"
>> Did it mean t h e r e? R.
>> All right. Uh, help us out, brother
Julius, with the spelling there.
>> No, it means exactly what it means.
there, which is a possessive noun, t h e
i r. Uh, let's look at who these little
ones are. She Let's read her scripture.
Uh,
>> uh, which is Matthew 18:10-14,
>> right? Read verse 10. Tenzil,
>> take heed that ye despise not one of
these little ones. For I say unto you,
that in heaven their angels do always
behold the face of my father which is in
heaven.
>> Now, let's address who these little ones
are. Back up and read verse one.
Sometimes you can't you can't just go to
the middle of a chapter to get an
answer. You got to start with the
beginning. Go ahead.
>> At the same time came the disciples unto
Jesus, saying, "Who is the greatest in
the kingdom of heaven?" The disciples
asked Jesus, "Who is the greatest? Which
is the greatest? Or who is the greatest
in the kingdom of heaven?" Look at Jesus
response. Pay attention to what he
called. Go ahead.
>> And Jesus called a little child unto
him.
>> A little what?
>> A little child.
>> He called a little child unto him. Go
ahead and finish it.
>> And sent him in the midst of them. and
said verily I say unto you, except ye be
converted and become a little children,
ye shall not enter into the kingdom of
heaven.
>> Continue reading verse five.
>> And who so shall receive one such little
child in my name receiveth me?
>> Uh-huh.
>> But who so shall offend one of these
little ones which believe
>> one of these what
>> little ones?
>> These little ones. What? Little
children. Go ahead. was believe in me,
it were better for him that a meal stone
were hung about his neck, and that he
were drowned in the depths of the sea.
>> Now, skip down and answer your own
question. Verse 10.
>> So, take heed that he despised not one
of these little ones, for I say unto
you, that in heaven their angels do
always behold the face of my father
which is in heaven. So those ang those
those angels have uh are assigned to
little children just like the book tells
us the angel of the Lord encampeth
around him that fearth them and keep his
commandments. Those children have angels
assigned in to him. Verse 14 and we're
done.
Even so, it is not the will of your
father which is in heaven that one of
these littlest ones should perish.
>> Because the Lord loved children and he
told the disciples
uh suffer not the little ones that come
unto me. That's the little children and
the there is there represents their
angels when you abuse a child or miss uh
h
mess over children. Hey, the Lord said
their angels are behold and watching and
the Lord will deal with that person.
That's all I got.
>> I'd like to add a little more to it.
>> All right.
>> Not only little children, he said, but
those that become like a child. In other
words, those that are innocent
>> and turn to the Lord and are not guilty.
Uh uh and and you know it's you got
baptized now you done wash your sins
away and you just like a child. you're
innocent. But if anybody come against
them, even though they grown up,
still
their angels are stand before God
because like like it was said earlier
that the angel of the Lord camp around
encamp around all those that fear him.
or he's talking about a child or either
a person that's become innocent as a
child by being baptized and walking in
the Lord in the Lord uh uh uh uh uh word
that mean they are children of God but
it's got two sides to it. Let me show
you uh uh if I can guest caller, let's
go to first John the 2 chapter and let's
look at what John calls. And these are
uh uh grown people
piggybacking on what guest caller is
saying. First John chapter 2 and just
verse one.
My little children, these things write I
unto you that ye sin not. And if any man
sin, we have an advocate with the
father, Jesus Christ, the righteous.
>> So like uh guest caller said, John is
talking about converts and people that
have come into the truth and been
baptized and washed away their sins. So
that's a spiritual side of it also.
>> Thank you, Gu.
>> Yep, that is correct. And be baptized in
Jesus' name and not the father, the son,
and the holy ghost. Those are titles.
All right, we hope that that answered
your question as we move on to our next
>> next one. Be alert as how can you be
influenced by evil spirits if they are
under chains of darkness?
>> These evil spirits are everywhere.
Brother Jerome, what you got?
You don't have to literally see a a
fallen angel in order to be influenced
by a fallen angel. And I want to show
you some examples of that. Okay. Um
let's go to 2 Corinthians the 4th
chapter though.
2 Corinthians the 4th chapter and read
verse 3-4. And then we're going to go to
Revelations after that.
You get it? Go ahead and read.
>> But if our gospel be hid, it is hid to
them that are lost.
And whom the God of this world have
blinded the minds of them which believe
not and lest the light of the glorious
gospel of Christ who is the image of God
should shine unto them.
>> He said whom the God of this world it
says Satan have deceiveth the whole
world.
>> Right? He said he blind the minds. So he
even you don't necessarily have to see
Satan, but he can influence your mind,
you know, if you ain't got the spirit of
the Lord
>> in your mind,
>> you know. But let's look at two other
places. Let's go to Revelations 12 verse
3-4. And we gonna tie that with Luke
Tanzel. Okay.
Revelations 12 and read verse 3-4.
>> Go ahead.
And there appear another wonder in
heaven. And behold, a great red dragon
having seven heads and 10 horns and
seven crowns upon his head. And it tells
you the third part of the stars of
heaven and did cast them to the earth.
And the dragon stood before the woman
which was ready to be delivered for to
devour her child as soon as it was born.
>> Okay, we know the great great red dragon
here is Satan, the devil, and he stood
before the woman, but he looked a little
different. He stood before her to devour
the child that came out of this woman as
soon as she was born.
But he didn't stand before
>> this child looking like Satan the devil.
He stood before him in the person of
Herod the great.
Okay. So now let's go to
uh Luke
the second chapter.
Read verse verse 1-4. We going to skip.
And it came to pass in those days that
there were a decree from Caesar Augustus
that all the world should be taxed.
And this taxing was first made when
Sirenist was governor of Seria.
Okay. I meant to say Matthew's the
second chapter. That's my mistake.
Believe it's Matthew. Yeah. Sorry. Let's
go to Matthew the 2 chapter
and read verse 1-4.
Go ahead.
>> And when Jesus was born in Bethlehem of
Judea in the days of Herod the king,
behold, there came wise men from the
east of Jerusalem.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Saying, where is he that is born king of
the Jews? We have seen his star in the
east, and I come to worship him. Uhhuh.
Go ahead.
>> And when Herod the king had heard these
things, he was troubled and all
Jerusalem with him.
>> Uhhuh. Verse four.
>> When they had gathered together all the
chief priests and scribes of the people
together, he demanded of them where
Christ should be born.
>> It is the child that came out the woman
in his revelations. And Satan stood
before to devour the child as soon as
she was born. Okay? He came in the
person of Herod the Great. All right. So
skip down to verse seven. Read it to the
eight.
>> Then Herod, when he had privately called
the wise men, inquired of them
diligently what time the star appeared.
>> And he sent them to Bethlehem and said,
"Go and search diligently for the young
child." And when you have found him,
bring me word again that I may come and
worship him also.
>> Yeah. He don't want to worship the
child. He want to kill the child. Skip
down to verse 13.
And when they were departed, behold, the
angel of the Lord appeared to Joseph in
a dream, saying, "Arise, and take the
young child and his mother, and flee
into Egypt, and be thou there until I
bring thee word, for Herod will seek the
young child to destroy him."
>> Yeah. So, you ain't got to see Satan. He
can influence you. And he was
influencing Herod the Great to kill the
the child Jesus. That's all I got.
All right, thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> next one, Reneica Evans asked about the
first and second resurrection.
Uh she says, "If Jesus is the first
fruit and was the first resurrected from
the dead, why is first resurrection not
counted as the second and the second not
counted as the third?"
>> All right, dealing with the
resurrection. Just call them.
Look, this has been dealt with before,
but I say this, everybody know that in
Colossians, the first chapter that Jesus
the firstborn from the dead. But I want
to read you what Revelation said.
Revelation 20, read verse 4-6.
Read it when you get there. And I saw
thrones, and they that sat upon them.
And judgment was given unto them. And I
saw the souls of them that were beheaded
for the witness of Jesus, and for the
word of God, and which had not worshiped
the beast, neither his image, neither
had received his mark upon their
forehead. For in their hands,
and they lived and reigned with Christ a
thousand years.
>> Go ahead.
But the rest of the dead live not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection.
>> This is the what resurrection?
>> The first resurrection.
>> Keep reading.
>> But blessed and holy is he that have
power in the first resurrection. On such
the second death have no power. But they
should be preached of God and of Christ
and shall reign with him a thousand
years.
>> Okay. Now,
this said first resurrection. That's
what it said.
>> Yeah.
>> Now,
go to the seventh verse. And we going to
see what the uh see if it mention a
second resurrection at all. Go ahead and
read.
>> And when the thousand years are expired,
Satan shall be loosed out of his prison.
Now that's when Satan going to be loosed
out of his prison and he going to go and
deceive the whole world and after that
he going to go rather and get a group of
people going to come against the camp of
the saints and fire is going to fall
down from heaven and uh and kill them.
But it says the first resurrection and
then it talks about the rest of the dead
live not until the thousand year is over
with. The Bible said the first
resurrection. Everybody know that Jesus
was the firstborn from the dead. But
this is not talking about the one that
created the world and became man and
rose again. He's talking about people
that was dug out of the ground
and they was never God.
He's talking about people that come from
among men, not God that became man and
went back to being God. But if it was
counting that, then it would have said
the third resurrection. The Bible said
the first resurrection and a thousand
years later the rest of the dead are
going to be raised. And that's what's
written in the book.
That's not an opinion. That is the word
of God.
Plus again too, I don't see no salvation
being uh gotten just by deciding how
many resurrections it is.
Salvation is decided by how much you
obey what's written in this book and
keep God's laws. That's all I got to
say.
>> All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Little Mama Hayes asked, "When
Jesus is coming down to reign for 1,000
years, the dead in Christ will be raised
first. Are these only those who have
been killed for the word of God?
Example, martyrs."
>> All right, we talking about another
resurrection here. What do you say,
brother Jerome?
Well, the latter part of that question
you said, are these only those who have
been killed for the word of God? And no,
they're not. Okay, let's look at some
examples of of of others who were going
to be killed for the word of God during
that time where eventually when that
seven trumpet blow, he'll come the Lord.
Okay? Right?
>> For example, during the times of the
great tribulation. Okay, let's go read
that. Revelations um 11.
And we going to read verse 3-5.
You get it? Go ahead and read.
>> And I will give power unto my two
witnesses. They shall prophesize 1,23
score days clothed in sackcloth.
But these are the two olive trees and
the two candlesticks standing before the
God of the earth. And if any man will
hurt them, fire and proceed out of their
mouth and devour their enemies. If any
man will hurt them, he must in this
manner be killed.
But these have power to shut heaven that
it rain not in the days of their
prophecy, and have power over waters to
turn them to blood, and to smite the
earth with all plagues as often as they
will. And when they shall have finished
their testimony, the beast that ascended
out of the bottomless pit shall make war
against them, and shall overcome them
and kill them.
>> Okay? And so when you read that
Revelations 20 for example, it talk
about those that were beheaded
>> for the word of God. The two witnesses
weren't beheaded, okay? But they were
killed for the word of God. Okay, let's
go to uh the sixth chapter. Read verse 9
through 11.
Go ahead and read it when you get it.
And when they had opened the fifth seal,
I saw under the altar the souls of them
that were slain for the word of God. And
for the testimony which they held, and
they cried with a loud voice, saying,
"How long, O Lord, holy and true, dost
thou not judge and avenge our blood of
them that dwell on the earth?" And white
robes were given unto every one of them.
And it was said unto them that they
should rest for a little season until
their fellow servants also and their
brethren that should be killed as they
were as they were should be fulfilled.
>> Yeah. you know, so um and there's so
many other places we can read. You know,
you we not going to go there, but you
can write down Daniel's the 11th chapter
versus 11 uh verses 31-35.
It talk about some some people that's
going to get killed too for the word of
God, you know. Yeah. Just before the
Lord before the Lord come during that
time of the great tribulation. All
right. That's all I got. That's what I
got.
>> Look, read the question again.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. The question is,
when Jesus is coming down to reign for
1,000 years, the dead in Christ will be
raised first. Are these only those who
have been killed for the word of God?
Example, martyrs.
>> The word is no. Abraham died of old age.
Isaac died of old age. Jacob died of old
age. The 12 patriots, the sons that make
up the 12 tribes of Israel, died of old
age. Peter died of old age. All died of
old age. All of these guys that walk
right with God and was straight with
God. Everyone Jeep laws and stances that
found out found out found acceptable are
going to be in the first resurrection.
The people that got killed among the
people the righteous men,
it's the righteous that's going to be in
the first resurrection. Whether he died
by force or died of old age,
that's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question with a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:01.
Zion Israel asks,
"What age should one be baptized
according to the scriptures?"
>> At what age should one be baptized
according to the scriptures? Guess
caller.
That's at the age that the Lord owe you
responsible.
Let's give you a good example. Let's go
into Numbers the 14th chapter
and read verse 27-
29.
>> How long shall I bear with this evil
congregation which murmured against me?
Have heard the murmuring of the children
of Israel? Was they murmured against me?
But say unto them, as truly as I live,
sayeth the Lord, as he hath spoken in my
ear, so will I do to you. Your carcass
your carcasses shall fall in the
wilderness, and all that were numbered
of you, according to the whole number
from 20 years old and upward, which have
murmured against me.
>> Now listen, I'm pretty sure you have
some 18 to 19 year old and murmured
against God, too.
But the Lord didn't uh didn't hold him
responsible. These are from a from 20
years and older.
You ain't going you are going to die in
this wilderness. Go to numbers
32 and verse 11.
Read it
32.
Surely none of the men that came
surely
none of the men that came up out of
Egypt from 20 years old and upward shall
see the land which I swear unto Abraham,
unto Isaac, and unto Jacob, because they
have not wholly followed me.
So now it's letting you know that now
you got all these people that come out
of out of the uh uh Egypt every and and
uh uh
they ming against God.
And I'm pretty sure you have some like I
said 16, 17, 18, and 19 year old uh uh
men and women who m against God along
with everybody else. But they was not
held responsible. The Lord only held
them responsible for 20 years and older.
And that tells me that when you start
when you're old enough to be held
responsible, then you're old enough to
enter into a blood covenant. In other
words, be baptized in the name of Jesus
because you're old enough to know what
you're doing and what you're getting
into.
So according to the Lord's uh uh uh uh
time when he hold you responsible that
is the time then that you can make a
responsible move and and the most
responsible move you can make is get
baptized in the name of Jesus and he
held you responsible at the at 20 years
and older
minimum 20. If you're 19 years old,
then the Lord is not holding you
responsible
according to this scripture. That's all
I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Our next one, Adam says, "Can you
explain Deuteronomy 12 verse 15?" It
says, "According to the blessing of the
Lord, thy God, which he has given thee,
the unclean and the clean may eat
thereof."
Did the Lord allow them to eat unclean?
>> No. Lord did not allow them to eat
unclean.
And the law of God when it comes to what
you can eat and what you cannot eat is a
sanctification. It sets you apart from
the rest of the world. Everybody on this
panel is sanctified according to the
word of God about what we eat and what
we don't eat. But let's go in Leviticus
11 first and then we'll come back to
your scripture and let's see who set up
this dietary law which he meant to be
kept throughout generations.
Leviticus 11. And let's read one and two
tenzel. Then we going to skip down. Go
right ahead.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses and to
Aaron, saying unto them, speak unto the
children of Israel, saying, These are
the beasts which ye shall eat among all
the beasts that are on the earth.
>> So this is the the Lord speaking to
Moses, saying, hey, and the Lord
speaking to Moses and to Aaron, saying,
speak unto the rest of the people and
let them know what this law is saying
here. Skip down and read 43 and 44 for
me. Go ahead.
>> You shall not make yourselves abominable
with any creeping thing that creepeth,
neither shall you make yourselves
unclean with them that ye shall be
defiled thereby.
>> Because once you eat the things that the
Lord say do not eat, then you start to
make yourselves abominable because you
eating what he said do not eat. Read.
>> For I am the Lord your God. You shall
therefore sanctify yourselves, and you
shall be holy, for I am holy. Neither
shall ye defile yourselves with any man
of creeping thing that creepeth upon the
earth.
>> Yes. Now, skip down and read 46 and 47
because the Lord is saying that there is
a separation here. Go ahead. This is the
law of the beasts and of the fowls and
of every living creature that moveth in
the waters and of every creep creature
that creepeth upon the earth.
>> Difference between the unclean and the
clean and between the beast that may be
eaten and the beast that may not be
eaten.
>> So when the Lord gave this law back here
in Leviticus for the beast you can eat
and you cannot eat, those same laws are
still good today.
So, we still have to respect God's
dietary law that is written in this
Leviticus 11 and it's in Deuteronomy 12.
But let's turn and go the way you
requested which was uh Deuteronomy 12.
And when you get there
at Deuteronomy 12, now we're going to
pick it up at that verse 15. But keep in
mind now when we talking about clean and
unclean here, we're talking about
people,
the people that keep the laws of God and
the ones that do not. Read verse 15. Go
ahead.
>> Notwithstanding, thou mayest kill and
eat flesh in all thy gates. So
whatsoever thy soul lusteth after
>> now whatsoever thy soul lusteth after is
according to the law of God that we just
read. You can eat off of the list of
what he said you can eat. Go ahead.
>> According to the blessing of the Lord
thy God which he have given thee the
unclean and the people
>> the unclean people and the clean people.
Go ahead, brother.
>> May eat thereof as of the road book and
as of the heart.
>> So Lord was saying that the we talking
about unclean people here, right?
>> And clean people here. So that is where
the Lord is saying that the unclean
people hey that they can eat of the food
also. But the Lord intended for his
dietary law to be from one end of the
earth clean to the other. for all of his
sons and daughters. And also, let's just
throw verse 16 in there because people
are still doing this, too. Go ahead.
>> Only ye shall not eat the blood. You
shall pour it upon the earth as water,
>> right? So, all that blood soup and
eating your meat rare with all that
blood in it, you're not supposed to do
that. You should cook it until that is
gone.
So when you talk about, you know, the
clean and unclean, the Lord was talking
about people there, but his dietary law
is good until this day. And we hope that
you have eyes to see that. That's all I
got.
>> And again, u
>> I say something.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Whoever asked this question simply
cannot read. He said the clean and the
unclean may eat thereof. If it didn't
say that they may eat the clean, uh that
the clean and uncle
uh the clean and unclean may be eaten.
He said the clean and unclean may eat
thereof.
>> If you read then that you know that this
question should not haven't even been
asked. So you speak for itself that one
passes right there.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Right. And again, like the guest caller
said and you said, Brother Cornell,
we're talking about people. We're not
talking about the beast. We're talking
about clean and unclean people.
>> Hey, we go to one other place. Let's go
to Deuteronomy 15 and read verse 22.
Deuteronomy 15 and 22. Read that
Tanzanel when you can.
>> And thou shalt eat it within thy gates.
The unclean and the clean person shall
eat it alike as the road book and as the
heart.
>> There you go.
>> All right. Good bag up there, Brother
Dre. Appreciate that. Hope that answered
your question there that it was talking
about people like the sister, Brother
Dre, the guest calling myself. See? All
right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next question. Charlotte T asks, "If my
spouse and I constantly fight and she
has to leave, can we split or am I
obligated to stay married to her?"
>> Brother Julius, give some advice on this
question here. If you're constantly, if
you and your spouse is constantly
fighting, let's go over to Matthew the
19th chapter and let's look what Jesus
said.
Matthew 19, we going to pick it up at
verse three. Corn uh uh uh brother
Tanzel.
Matthew 19 and3 or are you obligated to
stay with her? First of all, when you
married her, when you was dating and
then you married her, you took vows.
Go ahead and read verse three.
>> The Pharisees also came unto him
tempting him and saying unto him, "Is it
lawful for a man to put away his wife
for every cause? Because you're arguing
and constantly arguing, that's not a
cause." Go ahead.
>> And he answered and said unto them,
"Have you not read that he which made
them at the beginning made them male and
female?
and said, "For this cause should a man
leave father and mother, and shall
cleave to his wife, and they twain shall
be one flesh."
>> Continue.
>> Wherefore they are no more twain, but
one flesh. So what therefore have God
have joined together? Let not man put
aunder.
>> But now they use it today for any
reason. Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> They said unto him, why did Moses then
command to give a writing of the
horsemen and to put her away?
And he said unto them, Moses, because of
the hardness of your heart, suffer you
to put away your wives. But from the
beginning it was not so.
>> You got some people that was back in
those day that was aggressively abusing
their spouses. Go ahead. Look what Jesus
said to read. Let look what Jesus said.
Go ahead.
But I say unto you, whosoever shall put
away his wife, except it be for
fornication, and shall marry another
committh adultery. And who so marry of
her which is put away do commit
adultery.
>> Now, let's go and look at it from
another point. 1 Corinthians the 7th
chapter,
and we going to pick this up at verse
10. Look what Paul said.
When you get here, go ahead. 1
Corinthians 7 and pick it up at verse
10. Go ahead.
>> And unto the Mary, I command yet not I,
but the Lord, but let not the wife
depart from her husband.
>> Uh-huh.
>> But and if she depart, let her remain
unmarried, or be reconciled to her
husband, and let
>> So if you all are constantly fighting,
somebody need to take a breath. Somebody
need to take a drive, take a walk, cool
off. come back and uh uh uh and and um
and uh communicate. Reconcile means to
restore friendly relationships.
Reconcile. Go ahead.
>> To her husband and let not the husband
put away his wife.
>> And let not the husband put her away.
But
>> but to the rest,
>> you can't make no You can't make nobody
stay. That's between you and the Lord.
We cannot tell you what to do. We can
only read what the book say. It's true.
Relax, talk about it calmly, and work it
out. Did anybody else want to add to
that?
Oh, brother. I just think sometimes a a
good look at the man in the mirror can
help you change your ways, too.
>> Man,
>> the Lord said he hate putting away.
Yeah,
>> you took a bow.
>> Yep.
>> Go ahead.
>> And pray. All right.
So, we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Heather May asks, "When we are
in court and asked to swear on God, what
is the correct response to keep in line
with man and God's laws?"
>> Yeah. When you're in court and asked to
swear on God, what is the correct
response to keep in line with man and
God laws? And we all know some about
that jury duty, too. Brother Dre, what
you say?
>> Yeah, I got jury duty coming up. So,
yes. Um, you can affirm. You don't have
to swear. But let's look at a couple of
things. Let's go to Numbers 30 and we
going to read verse two there. Numbers
30 and2. Read that. when you get it.
>> TZ
and verse two.
>> Yeah. And and to affirm means to state
as a fact and to assert strongly and you
doing this publicly. They want you to to
swear, but you can affirm, but whatever
you say, you got to state the fact. Go
ahead.
If a man vow a vow unto the Lord, or
swear an oath to bind his soul with a
bond, he shall not break his word. He
shall do according to all that proceedth
out of his mouth.
>> That's right. So if you going to do
that, then you got to not break your
word and whatever you say like in in
Exodus 20, you cannot bear false
witness. Exodus 20 and 16 tell you about
bearing false witness. But let's look at
what Jesus said. Let's go to Matthew the
5th chapter. Matthew 5 and pick it up at
verse 33. Matthew 5 and 33. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Again, you have heard that it have been
said by them of old time, thou shalt not
for swear thyself, but but shall perform
unto the Lord thy oath.
But I say unto you, swear not at all,
neither by heaven, for it is God's
throne,
nor by the earth, for it is his
foottool,
>> neither by Jerusalem, for it is the city
of the great king.
>> That's right. So swear not at all,
affirm,
and whatever you say, let it be that
that is true. Verse 37. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Let your communication be yay, yay, nay,
nay. Whosoever is more than these cometh
of evil.
>> That's right. So when you go to court,
they have you can tell them, listen, I
don't uh I don't swear. I don't make
that kind of vow by my faith. I affirm.
>> Yes,
>> you do that. That's all I got. I went to
court and the judge, "Do you swear to
Taylor?" I said, "I affirm." That means
yes, it's true.
>> Yep. And they do accept that with no
problems.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Detroit. Troy Price asks
in Matthew 19:E9
it says, "Whoever leaves except for
fornication,
are the terms adultery and fornication
interchangeable?
If not, can you give an example being
that the term fornication was used in
lie of the in lie of adultery?
>> All right, got a little bit in that
question, but let's go to Matthew 19 and
verse 9 and the guest caller will take
it from there.
And I say unto you, whosoever shall put
away his wife, except it be for
fornication, and shall marry another
committeth adultery. And who so marry
her which is put away do commit
adultery.
>> Now see you this Jesus what Jesus said
and people that have some understanding
of the scripture know what he is talking
about.
Now let's go into uh uh uh Deuteronomy
the 22nd chapter
and first we're going to read 13 and 14.
Read it when you get there.
If a man take a wife and go in unto her,
and hate her, and give occasion of
speech against her, and bring up an evil
name upon her, and say, I took this
woman, and when I came to her, I found
her not a maid.
>> What? What verse was that?
>> 14.
>> Go ahead.
Then shall the father of the dames and
her mother take and bring forth the
tokens of the damel virginity unto the
elders of the city in the gate. And the
damsome father shall say unto the
elders, I gave my daughter unto this man
to wife and he hated her.
So now this is all predicated on when uh
uh when Israel was a people or either a
woman said that she ain't never laid
with a man,
then you go and you marry her on the
premises that she is a virgin. And when
you go with her, go into her and you
find out that she ain't no virgin, then
the whole thing was built on a lie.
So now in the old days, a guy married a
woman and she was no virgin
uh and and uh he bring up the
acquisition. He had to prove it. But if
the proof was against her, then he could
put her away. Skip down to verse 20 and
read 20 and 21.
But if this thing be true, and the token
of virginity be not found in the damsel,
then they shall bring out the damsel to
the door of her father's house, and the
men of the city shall stone her with
stones that she die, because she hath
wrought folly in Israel to play the
in her father's house. So shall
thou put evil away from among you.
>> Now that's the way it was. You know, it
wasn't just put it away. You kill her.
But then the Lord softened and it
started and and let you know this the
same thing with with uh uh uh uh with
Mary. Let's go into Matthew the 21st uh
Matthew the 1st chapter and read verse
18- 20.
Now when the birth of Jesus Christ was
on this wise when as the mother of Mary
was expounded to Joseph before they came
together she was found with child of the
Holy Ghost. Then Joseph her husband
being a just man and not willing to make
her a public example was minding to put
her away privately.
But while he thought on these things,
behold, the angel of the Lord appeared
unto him in a dream, saying, Joseph,
thou son of David, fear not to take unto
thee Mary, thy wife, for that which is
conceived in her is of the Holy Ghost.
>> Now, in the old days, you know, they
would take out the stone of the death,
but then Joseph was a just man. He
didn't want to have Mary stoned at her
death because she was supposed to be a
virgin, but how your virgin going to be
pregnant,
>> right?
>> So he put her away. So the angel told
him, "Look here. This is the child of
the Holy Ghost cuz Jesus came through."
But the Lord had already softened that.
And let me show you where. Let's go into
Deuteronomy the 24th chapter and read
verses 1 through3.
Each
When a man have taken a wife and married
her, and it come to pass that she find
no favor in his eyes, because he have
found some uncleanness in her, then let
him write her a bill of divorcement, and
give it to her hand, and send her out of
his house.
And when she is departed out of his
house, she may go and be another man's
wife.
And if the
Go ahead. No. What verse was that?
>> That was the end of two.
>> Go ahead.
>> And if the latter husband hate her and
write her a bill of divorcement and give
it it in her hand and send her out of
his house, or if the latter husband die,
which took her to be his wife, her
former husband which sent her away may
not take her again to be his wife. After
that she is defiled.
Now the whole thing is
now and the only uncleanness and Jesus
let you know that was that he would
recognize for putting a woman away if if
she was supposed to be a virgin and she
said she was a virgin and you thought
she was married to a virgin and when you
marry and lay with you find out she's
not a virgin then you put her away.
Got nothing to do with adultery.
But when it come to committing adultery,
if you you commit adultery, then the
Lord used to have you stoned to death.
But now, right now, what you do, you can
put her away. So adultery and
fornication is not interchangeable. You
just got to understand what's written.
It was if a woman supposed to be a
virgin and she said she was a virgin and
you married her and find out that she
was not,
you don't stone them to death no more.
Have them stone to death no more. You
just put them away just like Jesus said.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right,
Sister Deborah. Hope that answered their
question. Are we going into new
territory?
>> Uh yes. Uh we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, July the 16, 2025.
Um BJ asked for you to explain Luke 16
verse9.
Is this physical, spiritual, or both?
>> Luke 16 and9. Let's open it up to the
panel.
Luke 16 and9.
Go ahead, brother Tanzel. And the panel
will take it from there.
>> And I say unto you, make to yourself
friends of of the manner of
unrighteousness, that when ye fail, they
may receive you into everlasting
habitation.
>> All right. Open to the
>> I deal with it. Back up to the first and
start reading down.
And he said also unto his disciples,
there was a certain rich man which had a
steward, and the same was accused unto
him that he had wasted his goods.
And he called them, and said unto him,
How is it that I hear this of thee,
giving account of thy stewardship, for
thou mayest be no longer steward?
And then the steward said within
himself, but what shall I do? My Lord
taketh away from me the stewardship. I
cannot dig to beg. I am ashamed.
>> I am resolved.
>> Keep going.
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> I am resolved what to do that when I am
put out of the stewardship that they may
receive me into their house. So he
called every one of his lords deps unto
him and said unto the first, but how
much oldest thou unto my lord? And he
said a 100 measures of oil. And he said
unto him, take thy bill and sit down
quickly and write 50. Then said he to
another, and how much owest thou? And he
said, 100 measures of wheat. And he said
unto him, take thy bill and write four
scores. And the Lord commanded commanded
the unjust steward because he had done
wisely. For the children of this world
are the their generation wiser than the
children of light.
And I say
>> pay attention. Pay attention now. First
thing he called them unfaithful servant.
Now he going to say now the children of
this world
are wiser than the children of what?
>> Of life.
>> Now so you got two different people. Go
ahead and read.
>> And I say unto you, make to yourselves
friends of the manner of
unrighteousness,
that when ye fail,
they may receive you unto everlasting
inhabitation.
>> And that's however long that is, he
already made him unjust steward. And he
called him a child of the world. So, so
and the children of this world are wiser
than children of light. In short, if you
ain't going to serve God, you may as
well get all you can out of this world
because you got to choose who you going
to serve. Somebody go quickly and find a
scripture where he say you cannot serve
God and mammon to
verse 13.
>> Yeah,
>> read it. No servant can serve two
masters. For either he will hate the one
and love the other, or else he will hold
to the one and despise the other. You
cannot serve God and manner.
>> So that's it. So you ain't going to
serve right, then you may as well go on
and make friends with the world and get
all you can out of it cuz you going to
the liquor fire, mister.
>> Right.
>> That's all it's saying. That's all I
have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Uh, next one. Bobby Reed says,
"I know
pork is not allowed in the Old
Testament, but in the New Testament,
does it change?" Uh, first Timothy verse
4.
First Timothy
4 verse 4 is given.
>> All right. It doesn't change that we
know of. Brother Julius, what you say?
>> I thought you told me to handle this.
>> Oh.
Um I think you just handled Yeah, you
just handled
>> that was number one.
>> Yeah,
>> I got this, too.
>> All right.
So, first Timothy 4
>> and four. For every creature of God is
good and nothing to be refused if it be
received with thanksgiving.
>> Now back up to verse one and start
reading down before.
Now the spirits speak of expressively
that in the latter time some shall
depart from the faith, giving heed to
seducing spirits and doctrines of
devils, speaking lies and hypocrisy,
having their conscience sear with a hot
iron, forbidding to marry, and
commanding to abstain from meat which
God have created to be received with
thanksgiving of them which believe and
know the truth. But every creature of
God is
>> now pay attention to that. First thing
is they going to tell you not to get
married.
>> Right?
>> Second thing is he said all these mess
all meats are good for those that
believe and know the truth. You
understand the word know?
>> Go ahead.
>> Every creature of God is good and
nothing to be refused if it be received
with thanksgiving.
So it is good for what it was created to
be,
>> right?
>> And if you know the truth, you know what
it was created to be. Now let's go into
Romans 14 and 14. We want to point out
something here cuz Paul is saying the
same thing in another way. 14 and 14.
>> Brother.
>> Yeah. I I know
and am persuaded by the Lord Jesus that
there is nothing unclean of itself but
to him that esteem anything to be
unclean it is him I mean to him it is
unclean
>> okay that nothing is unclean to itself
but whoever it is that esteem
or say it is unclean to him it is
unclean isn't that what they're saying
Right.
>> Well, let's go back and see who is the
one that esteemed a pig is unclean.
Let's go to Leviticus 20 chapter.
Leviticus chapter 20 and read verses 20
and 25.
You should therefore put difference
between clean beasts and unclean and
between unclean files and clean. You
shall not make yourselves abominable by
beasts or by fouls or by any manner of
living thing that creepeth on the ground
which I have separated from you as
unclean.
So who's talking there? That's God
talking.
So he said which I have separated from
you as unclean. So who esteemed pig is
unclean?
>> The Lord.
>> The Lord did
>> right. So if it's unclean to God, then
it's unclean to everybody else.
>> Let's go a little further.
>> I'm going to show you what this God that
made it unclean is going to do. Let's go
into second Thessalonians the second
first chapter. Read verses 6-8.
2 Thessalonians 1 6-8.
Read it when you get there.
>> Seeing it is a righteous thing which God
to recompense tribulation to them that
trouble you and to you who are troubled
rest with us. When the Lord Jesus shall
be revealed from heaven with his mighty
angels
in flaming fire, taking vengeance of
them that know not God, and that obey
not the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ,
who shall be punished with everlasting
destruction from the presence of the
Lord and from the glory of his power.
>> So Jesus going to come prevail from
heaven and flame and fire, taking
vengeance on them that knew not God.
Ain't that what he said?
>> Yep.
>> Isaiah wrote about it first. Let's go
into Isaiah chapter 66.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Vers 15 through 17.
But behold, the Lord will come with fire
and with his chariots like a whirlwind
to render his anger with fury and his
rebuke with flames of fire. For by fire
and by his
So we talking about the same Lord, ain't
we?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> For by fire, by his word will the Lord
plead with all flesh. And the slain of
the Lord shall be many, and they that
sanctify themselves and purify
themselves of the garden behind one tree
in the
Listen. He said, "They that sanctify
themselves and purified themselves." Is
that what it say?
>> That's right.
In the garden behind what?
>> One tree in the midst eating swine
flesh.
>> Behind one tree in the midst eating
swine flesh and the abomination and the
mouse shall be consumed together sayeth
the Lord.
>> So that let you know that this same Lord
Jesus when he come you pig eater he
going to consume you too. And you know
better
>> because and the other part was it have
it changed? Well the one that extended
it ain't have it changed is is the one
that decided it was unclean. Have he
changed his mind? Let's see. Go to first
Corin go into uh uh 1 Corinthians the
10th chapter and let's see who it was
that gave Moses them the dietary law.
Who was it back there with them? 1
Corinthians 10 1-4.
Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye
should be ignorant, how that all our
fathers were under the clouds, and all
pass through the sea, and were all
baptized under Moses in the cloud and in
the sea, and that all eat the same
spiritual meat, and did all drink the
same spiritual drink. For they drink of
that spiritual rock that followed them,
>> and that rock was Christ.
>> Oh, so that was Jesus back there with
with Moses them. Isn't that correct?
>> That's right. brother
>> and he gave a dietary law. Now, do he
change? Go to Hebrews
chapter 13 and read verse 8.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Jesus Christ the same yesterday and
today and forever.
So now if he said yesterday you couldn't
eat pig
and he said today you can't eat pig and
he said forever you can't eat pig, there
ain't no change, isn't it?
>> No change.
>> See
>> what people don't understand is Paul was
warning you about the Catholic church
that they going in the time they go some
people going to come up departing from
the faith
forbidden to marry and eating meat.
That's a Catholic church. If you want to
be a priest, you can't marry. If you
want to hold a position, a woman in the
church, you can't marry either. You got
to be a nun.
And under the Saint Benedict order, it
was fast then. In the beginning, they
was not supposed to eat meat at all.
They was warning you about this religion
that's going to depart from the faith.
So, you be prepared when you see it. And
instead of people seeing it and
understanding and paying an attention to
what he's saying, they ain't want to use
it so they can eat something that God
told them not to eat.
>> That's right.
>> Gave it.
>> Jesus gave his dietary law. Nothing has
changed because he didn't change. And he
told you what he going to do to you if
you eating it when he come. Now you make
your choice. That's all I have to say.
>> And he also said in Malachi 3 and6, "For
I am the Lord, I change not."
>> That's right.
Correct.
It was all you.
[Music]
>> Yep. Just uh just keep the dietary law.
You can do it. You can do it. All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Sister Israel says, "Can you
help me understand first Thessalonians 4
11 and 12?"
Brother Jerome, can you help understand
1 Thessalonians 4 11 and 12?
>> Let's go read it.
And they ye study to be quiet, and to do
your own business, and to work with your
own hands, as we command you, that ye
may walk honestly towards them that are
without, and that ye may have lack of
nothing.
I want to deal with that. Um 11 first.
It says, "And that you study to be quiet
and to do your own business and to work
with your own hands." Let's go to uh 1
Peter chapter 4
and read verse 15 concerning that.
1 Peter 4 chapter 15.
But let none of you suffer as a murderer
or as a thief or as a evildoer or as a
busy body in other men's matter.
>> Yeah. That latter part of that verse I
want you to pay attention to.
you know, as a busy body and other man's
matters. Okay. And the second verse
said, "That ye may wa walk honestly
toward them that are without, that you
have
lack of nothing." Let's go to First
Peter chapter 2 verse 12.
We're going to go to Philippians after
that, Tanzel.
>> Okay. 1 Peter chapter 2
and read verse 12.
>> Having your conversations honest among
the Gentiles, that whereas they speak
against you as evildoers, they may by
your good works, which they shall behold
glorify God in the day of visitation.
>> Yeah. So you got to walk honestly before
the people cuz people are watching us
especially if we claiming to be servants
of of the Lord Jesus Christ. So your
works got to display that before the
people. So even though they speak evil
of you, hey your Lord know what's what
you doing, you know. So uh go to
Philippians chapter 4 and that'll be it.
Philippians chapter 4 verse 19.
Yeah. Go ahead and read.
>> But my God shall supply all your needs
according to his riches and glory by
Christ Jesus.
>> Yeah. So you won't have no need and
nothing. The Lord going to provide
all your needs. Just serve him. He'll
take care of you. That's all I got.
>> Yes, sir. And just like the book say
too, brother, study to show yourself
approved.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there. As we move on to our
next question and let's open this up to
the panel.
>> Yes. Luke Williams asks, "Does Galatians
11-13
refer to people who teach people need to
be circumcised?"
Galatians 5 11-13.
>> All right, why don't we go to that?
Galatians 5, read that 11 through13 and
then open it up to the panel.
>> And our brethren, if I yet preach
circumcisions, why do I yet suffer
persecution?
Then it is offense of the cross cease.
But I would they were even cut off which
trouble you. For brethren, ye have been
called unto liberty. Only use not
liberty for an occasion to the flesh,
but by love serve one another.
>> And the question again, Deborah,
>> that scripture referred to people who
teach people need to be circumcised.
All right. The
>> question is yes.
How can you teach something about the
covenant and you have broken the
covenant? What is it? What is it?
Genesis the uh 17th chapter.
>> Yes sir.
>> Go back there and see what the covenant
is. First thing the Lord talking about
the covenant. He going to start out at
at at the at the first and then skip
down to where where he tell you what his
covenant is.
Amen.
>> When Abram was 90 years old and n the
Lord appeared to Abram and said unto
him, I am the Almighty God to walk
before me and be thou perfect.
>> Verse 10.
>> This is my covenant which ye shall keep
between me and you and thy seed after
thee. Every man child among you shall be
circumcised, and you shall circumcise
the flesh of your foreskin, and there
shall be a token of the covenant betw
twix me and you. And he that is 8 days
old shall be circumcised among you and
be manchild of your generation. He that
is born in the house or bought with
money of any stranger which is not of
thy seed. He that is born in thy house
and he that is bought with thy money
must needs be circumcised and my
covenant shall be in your flesh for an
everlasting covenant. And the
uncircumcised manchild who fess up his
foreskin is that circumcised that soul
cut off from his people. He have broken
my covenant.
>> Pass up. He said must need back up and
read. And must need be circumcised.
Those are two strong words, aren't they?
>> That's right. Must needs be circumcised.
>> Those are absolutes.
>> Now start for man. Finish it.
He that is born in the house and he that
is bought without thy money must needs
be circumcised. And my covenant shall be
in your flesh for an everlasting
covenant.
And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not circumcised
that soul shall be cut off from his
people. You have broken my already cut
off. You just don't know it.
>> Cut off from his people. How many people
do that include?
>> It had nothing to do with Israel. That's
the covenant that God made with Abraham
and his seed. Ain't that correct?
>> Yeah. Go
>> to the 12th chapter of Exodus and we
going to start reading with the
ordinance of the p with the uh uh uh
with the Passover with the uh uh uh
ordinance of the Passover. I think it's
around 47 or something like that. 12:47
>> 43
>> 43 Go ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the ordinance of the Passover.
There should no stranger, eat thereof.
But every man's servant that is bought
for money when thou hast circumcised
him, then shall he eat thereof." A
foreigner,
>> that's just
the eat of the Passover, isn't it?
>> That's right.
>> Keep reading. A foreigner and a hired
servant shall not eat thereof.
Let me skip down.
>> Yeah.
>> 48. And when a stranger shall sjourn
with thee, and will keep the Passover to
the Lord, let all his males be
circumcised, and then let him come near
and keep it, and he shall be as one that
is born in the land. For no
uncircumcised person shall eat thereof,
one law shall be to him that is
homeborn, and unto the stranger that is
adjourned among you.
>> Now, that's eating of the Passover,
right?
>> Who is the Passover? Let's go and read
it. 1 Corinthians 5 and 7.
Purge out therefore the old leaven that
you may be a new lump as ye are
unleavened for even Christ our passover
is sacrificed for us.
>> So that mean you can't partake of Jesus
if you ain't a circumcised. Isn't that
correct?
>> That's right.
>> Let's go into Galatians the third
chapter.
>> I don't know what we got. I think we
start reading around the last place
where it starts off and say we are all
>> uh and what
>> for as many as you have been baptized
under Christ has put on Christ.
>> Back up to the verse before it.
>> Well, you are all the children of God by
faith in Christ Jesus.
>> Uhhuh. For as many of you as have been
baptized into Christ have put on Christ.
There is neither Jew nor Greek, there is
neither bond nor free. There is neither
male nor female, for ye are all one in
Christ Jesus. And if you be Christ, then
are you Abraham's seed and hes according
to the promise.
>> That's right. So what did Abraham's seed
have to do? circumcised.
>> Circumcised must need.
>> So now you have to be circumcised. Now
you are not under the first covenant.
Neither are you under the last covenant.
Now and and the Lord say you're going to
be cut off. So how is a dead man walking
going to teach somebody the word of God?
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Time check. Sister Deborah with our next
question.
>> Yes. The time is 8:50.
Christy Watson asks in first Corinians
16 verse 22, "What does Anthemus
Moriran means?" 1 Corinians 16 verse 22,
what does anthemus Moriran means?
>> It means to be accursed.
>> Yep. To be accur. and uh 16 and 22 and
uh
some pronounce it too. Anathema
Marinatha
as well.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. And you say to be a curse too. And
let's pick it up uh in verse 22.
If any man love not the Lord Jesus
Christ, let him be and anthemma and
athema marinatha,
the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be
with you. My love be with you all in
Christ Jesus. Amen.
>> Yep. So, like brother Julius was saying
too, hey, if you ain't got no no love
for the Lord Jesus Christ, hey, you in a
bad place. That's why
>> all that hate me love all that hate me
love death. That's that lake of fire.
Can't get no more church than that.
>> Yeah. So, hey, come on board and get
with Jesus. You won't regret it.
>> All right, we're going to go on to our
next question.
>> Next question. Washington asks, "Do you
have a sermon on the millennium reign?
If so, what is the name of it?" So, do
you have a sermon on the millennium
reign?
>> What's the lesson that we got on the
millennium ring,
which they talking about the thousand
years, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Is there a title that comes to mind to
the panel?
>> We got so many. Um,
>> yeah, we do. Um,
>> would it be
>> great tribulation?
>> Yeah, great tribulation. I'll think of
that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Great tribulation is
>> son of David.
>> Say that again.
>> The kingdom of the son of David.
>> The kingdom of the son of David. All
right. Any more?
All right. Well, we're going to leave
you with those two for time sake right
now and uh let's move on to our next
question.
Next question. Micah says, "How is it
a sin for us to eat unclean foods, but
not a sin to wear mixed fabrics?"
Leviticus 19 and 19 and Deuteronomy 22
verse 11. Did Jesus nail those laws to
the cross? So again, Micah says, "How is
it a sin for us to eat unclean foods,
but not a sin to wear mixed fabrics?"
Leviticus 19:1 19 and Deuteronomy 22:11
is given. They want to know, did Jesus
nailed those laws to the cross?
>> That dietary law is totally hands off.
We just covered a lot of stuff saying
that the Lord gave Moses and Aaron what
the dietary law was. Those things have
to be kept.
So that is not even the same title as
you talking about clothes here. So the
dietary law is actually in stone. And
let's go and read that. What did he say?
Leviticus 19 and 19. Let's open it up to
the panel. This is dealing with the
clothes.
>> You shall keep my statutes. Thou shalt
not let thy cattle ginger with a diverse
kind. Thou shall not sew thy fields with
mingled seed, neither shall a garment
mingle of linen and woolen come upon
thee.
Panel,
>> that was specific. It didn't talk about
every fabric
on the planet. It mentioned two fabrics.
So those are the two fabrics that's
mentioned in the verse. Those are the
two fabrics the Lord is referring to.
That's not talking about all fabrics.
>> All right.
>> That's all I going to say.
>> I notice I notice something very absent
there. And you know what it is? Or you
will be cut off from among your people
or I will consume you when I come. You
notice nothing like that is in there.
>> Nothing.
Oh,
>> and and and lastly,
you know, you you talking about in
comparison wearing mixed fabrics, which
is linen and woolen, which is
specifically mentioned.
Let let's go to uh Revelation 22 and
read verse 14 and 15
because loving a lie is a problem. And
if we read all these scriptures that
tell you about eating swine and you just
want to eat it anyway, that means you
loving a lie that came from the church
that's telling you in that you can eat
it. All you have to do is pray over it.
But verse five tell you in that Timothy
for it is sanctified by the word of God
and prayer. When did he sanctify it? In
Leviticus. And if you read Leviticus 11,
the end of those couple of verses, it
tells you plainly that he sanctified it.
But let's go to Revelation 22. Read
verses 14 and 15. Go ahead when you get
it, brother.
>> Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they have might have
right to the tree of life and may enter
in through the gates into the city. For
without thou are dogs and sorcerers and
hormongers and murderers and idoltors
and whosoever loveth and maketh a lie.
>> Now he said, "Blessed are they that do
his commandments." Now if you want to
believe a lie and eat the swine, go
ahead.
You making the choice for yourself, but
the book tells you it is unclean. Do not
do it.
and comparing linen and woolen to eating
swine, which is an abomination.
That should that should be problematic
for you.
But that's all I got on that.
>> I'd like to put a stamp on that in in uh
Revelation 21 and8.
But the fearful and unbelieving, and the
abominable, and murderers, and harmers,
and sorcerers, and idoltors, and all
liars, shall have their part in the lake
of fire, in the lake, which burnth with
fire and brimstone, which is the second
death.
>> I didn't see I didn't I didn't hear wool
and linen mixed in that, did you?
[Music]
No son.
>> Yeah. And um Yeah.
And so we ask that you know if that's
how you feel, hey, you should keep that
to yourself until the Lord open your
eyes. And do not tell other people that
because it is simply not true.
>> Animal sacrifices nailed to the cross.
>> So
>> that's it. I'm going to sister Deborah
time check users and next question.
>> All right, time is 8:58. Uh this will be
the last question. Norman Nicks asks
which uh they Okay, this is what Norman
Nicks asks. Why doesn't the IOG have a
feast for seven days for unleaven bread
and the feast of tabernacles?
Yes, caller, you want to close us out on
that final question there.
>> First thing is it say should eat
unleaven bread
for seven days. He didn't say even
though it's under the feast, but you
know even the day of atonement come
under feast, don't it?
>> Yes, it do.
>> But but you can't eat nothing on the day
of atonement.
As for his tabernacle, it said you
should have a feast for seven days. But
he said, "But on the first and the last
day, you should have a holy
convocation." Now, when you come
together having a feast at the glass,
all of the congregation together, that
is a holy convocation. So, I want to ask
the I want to say to the person that
asked the question,
what is a holy convocation?
And the book say you have it on the
first and the last day. Unle bread the
first and the seventh day. Tabernacle
the first and the eighth day.
Holy convocation is when you come
together and have a holy assembly the
whole church. Now I want to ask the
question if that's the case then why is
everybody coming together at the church
and having a holy convocation for seven
days and for eight days
whoever asked a question you go and find
out about that then come back that's all
I got to say
>> all right
so sister Deborah time check
>> 9 o'
>> 9 o'clock we have ran out of time we
want to thank you call from all around
the world who tuned in with us this
evening asking your questions. And we
want to say that if you submitted a
question and we didn't have a chance to
get to it, please don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah, take it, put it in
rotation and we will address that
question next Wednesday at the same
time. But until we all come together
again, we ask that you all be blessed,
be safe, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all. As brother
Tanzel closes us out.
>> Our Father which art in heaven, hallowed
be thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will
be done in earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever. Jesus name we